If you just got a Ninja Creamy for
Christmas, this is the video for you.
I'm going to give you a few quick tips
so your first pint actually comes out
good. First, mix your base really well.
Powders like sweeteners, binding agents,
extracts, or paste all sink and clump at
the bottom. I always use an immersion
blender and mix for about 30 to 60
seconds. You can also use a hand frother
or a regular blender. Tip two, use a
binding agent. This is huge for texture.
I always use zantham gum, but you can
also use guar gum or jell- pudding mix.
For both zantham gum and guar gum, you
need about 1/ quart teaspoon per pint.
And for the jell- pudding mix, you need
about one tablespoon. These are what
make Ninja Creamy ice [music] cream
thick and creamy instead of icy and
chalky. One of the biggest things I
could recommend. Tip number three,
freeze your pints for at least 16 hours,
ideally 24. Anything less, and it
probably won't freeze all the way
through, and your ice cream will be
super soft and soupy. Tip number four
has to do with the ice crystals that
inevitably form on the sides of your
pint. Before you spin, either run your
pint under hot water for 30 to 60
seconds or leave it out on the counter
for about 10 minutes. This helps melt
the ice on the sides and [music] makes a
massive difference in overall texture.
Tip number five is to use the light ice
cream setting, especially if you're
making protein ice cream. If you're
unfamiliar with all these settings on
the Ninja Creamy, light ice cream is one
of the longest and [music] most powerful
settings. This matters a ton when you're
making a low sugar and low-fat base
because they freeze much harder and need
more processing power. If your base is
softer though, like a banana base or a
higher fat or sugar base, the regular
ice cream setting can work well, too.
And one last thing, when it comes to
texture, if it comes out crumbly, do not
panic. That is completely normal. Just
respin it. And no, you don't need to add
milk in between spins. Adding milk
usually makes it too soft. So, if you
want complete control over your texture,
just respin it normally. Maybe it'll
take a couple more respins, but that's
worth the outcome of your entire pint.
And just remember, if your first pint
isn't perfect, that's completely normal.
You're just going to get better at using
the Ninja Creamy as time goes on.